The story of a wanna be who got to be.
Rock Star is a music, drama, comedy film directed by Stephen Herek.
A wannabe rock star who fronts a Pennsylvania-based tribute band is
devastated when his bandmates kick him out of the group he founded.
Things begin to look up for Izzy when he is asked to join Steel Dragon,
the heavy metal rockers he had been imitating for so long.
This film is loosely based on the true story of the band Judas Priest.
Chris 'Izzy' Cole, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Emily Poule, played by Jennifer Aniston.
Kirk Cuddy, played by Dominic West.
A.C., played by Jason Bonham.
Jorgen, played by Jeff Pilson.
Ghode, played by Zakk Wylde.
Rock Star is a 2001 American musical comedy-drama film directed by Stephen Herek,
written by John Stockwell, and starring Mark Wahlberg and Jennifer Aniston.
It tells the story of Chris "Izzy" Cole, a tribute band singer who
ascends to the position of lead vocalist in his favorite band.
The script was inspired by the real-life story of Tim "Ripper" Owens, a singer in a Judas Priest
tribute band who was chosen to replace singer Rob Halford when he temporarily left the band.
After optioning the filming rights to a New York Times
profile of Owens by Andrew Revkin, Warner Bros.
hired Stockwell to write the script.
Brad Pitt was initially signed to play the lead role, but left due to creative
differences, and Wahlberg was eventually hired for the part.
Rock Star garnered mixed reviews from critics, and was a box office failure,
grossing $19 million worldwide against a production budget of $57 million.
The film explores themes of rock star, success,
heavy metal, relationship problems.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.